This is a special month in India
Bu Hindistan’da özel bir ay
and it is nice that we are organizing this program during this month
ve Marga Sheersha adı verilen bu ayda,
called as the Margasheersha,
bu programı organize ediyor olmamız hoş.
means where Marga means the road and Sheersha is the head,
Marga, yol anlamına gelir ve Sheersha, ise baştır,
which leads you to the Epitome,
sizi kendisi bu ay olan,
that's the month. And in this month they worship
somut örneğe doğru yönlendirir. Bu ayda Guru’ya
Guru because of His birthday of Dattatreya
ibadet ederler çünkü Dattatreya’nın doğum günüdür
and also they worship Mahalakshmi.
ve aynı zamanda Mahalaksmi’ye de ibadet ederler.
That means this is the month of Shushumna,
Bu, bunun Shushumna ayı olduğu anlamına gelir ki,
where the people get out of
insanlar küçük arzularının
the bondages of smaller hankerings
esaretinden kurtulurlar
and enter into a new path of seeking
ve Mahalakshmi olan, Shushumna olan,
of Spirituality  that is Shushumna that is Mahalakshmi.
spiritüelliği aramanın yeni bir yoluna girerler.
Also on this, there are lots of  Pujas
Bu sırada aynı zamanda, pek çok pujalar vardır,
they do for four Thursdays,  the Puja of Mahalakshmi
Dört Perşembe günü,  pujalar yaparlar, Mahalakhsmi puja
because Mahalakshmi is worshipped on a Thursday
çünkü Guru prensibinin özü olarak,
as it is the essence of the Guru principle.
bir Perşembe gününde Mahalakshmi’ye ibadet edilir.
The Gurus have to satisfy the Mahalakshmi
Gurular, sadece saf Tanrı arayışı olan
principle, which is just pure seeking of God,
veya siz ne diyorsunuz, Shuddha Ichcha olan
or what do you call the Shuddha Ichha.
Mahalakshmi prensibini tatmin etmeliydiler.
Today is the Saturday as I enquired and the Puja was done in Poona
Bu gün Cumartesi, istediğim gibi , puja, Pune’de de
was also  on Thursday.
Perşembe günü yapıldı.
Thursday puja was the thing of the Mahalakshmi's Puja is started.
Perşembe pujası, Mahalakshmi’nin şeyi idi, puja başladı.
The day we did  puja in Mahalakshmi, there,
Mahalakshmi Puja yapıldığı gün orada, hepiniz gördünüz,
you saw hole  the water was giving away its exuberance
su nasılda, mucizevi pınarlar ortaya çıkararak
by putting up miraculous fountains.
taşkınlığından vazgeçiyordu.
And they became the clouds I believe
İnanıyorum ki onlar bulut oldular
because I heard at the time of the puja
çünkü duydum ki puja sırasında
rain started in Rahuri and it rained and rained and rained.
Rahuri’de yağmur başladı ve yağdı, yağdı ve yağdı.
And now this country which is under drought,
Şimdi bu ülke kuraklık altında,
people  don't even have water to drink we have rain.
insanların içmeye bile suyu yok, bizim yağmurumuz var.
So the whole thing works out according to the calendar
Yani her şey insan tarafından değil,
which is devised by God, not by human beings.
Tanrı tarafından tasarlanan takvime göre çalışıyor.
So today is an another day of Saturday,
Bu gün, sahilinde oturduğumuz
where we are sitting on the bank of Krishna river.
Krishna nehrindeki bir başka cumartesi günü.
See how it works out?
Bakın, nasıl da çalışıyor?
Krishna river represents the power of Shri Krishna.
Krishna nehri, Shri Krishna gücünü temsil eder.
So the Mahalakshmi Tattwa has to go to the Krishna's state,
Yani, Mahalaksmi Tatwa,  Krishna konumuna,
of the witness state and that's how we are here today
şahit konumuna  gitmelidir ve işte bu şekilde bizler
on this special occasion in Brahmapuri,
Brahmapuri’de,  bu özel vesile ile buradayız.
also the word Brahmapuri means where you feel the Brahma,
Aynı zamanda Brahmapuri, Brahma’yı hissettiğiniz yer anlamına gelir,
the Chaitanya which you can feel it on this earth.
Chaitanya’yı bu dünyada hissedebildiğiniz yerdir.
So when we are touring we are actually also internally, moving.
Yani biz tur yaparken, aslında içeriden de hareket ediyoruz.
Also there is Anthar Yoga which you are achieving.
Sizin ulaşmakta olduğunuz Anthar Yoga’da vardır.
So you should not mind little, little things here and there
Orada burada küçük küçük şeyleri düşünmemeli
but enjoy every bit of it.
ve bunun her bir parçasından neşe duymalısınız.
Yesterday also I was happy you all danced
Dün de hepiniz dans ettiniz
because yesterday was the day of Shakti, was the Friday.
Ben mutluydum çünkü dün Shakti günüydü, Cumaydı.
On the day of Shakti if you dance you will get that power within yourself.
Eğer Shakti gününde dans ederseniz, içinizdeki gücü elde edersiniz
And that's why you are looking much better now.
ve işte bu yüzden çok daha iyi görünüyorsunuz.
In My name if you dance you get the power, no doubt about it.
Eğer Benim adımla dans ederseniz, şüphe yok ki güç elde edersiniz.
And that's why here you have to achieve your Spiritual power,
İşte bu yüzden burada, ruhsal gücünüze,
your Spiritual peace and your Spiritual love.
ruhsal huzurunuza ve ruhsal sevginize ulaştınız.
All these things if you can achieve in India
Eğer bütün bu şeylere Hindistan’da ulaşabilirseniz,
you have done full justice to Me and to yourself.
Bana ve kendinize karşı, tamamıyla adil davranmış olursunuz.
It is not just a picnic or an outing, nothing of the kind,
Bu sadece bir piknik veya bir gezi değil, bu türden bir şey değil,
and working out internally all of you, now I am sure it will work out.
içsel bir çalışmadır bu. Şimdi, bunun işe yarayacağından eminim.
So have loving attitude towards all the other people
Burada bulunan, sizler için çok miktarda sevgi hisseden
who are here, who are feeling lots of love for you
bütün bu insanlara karşı, sizin sevecen bir tavrınız olsun
and they pay lot of attention, they don't want you to do any hard work
ve onlar çok dikkat koydular, sizin ağır iş yapmanızı istemiyorlar.
they want to look after you but you also try to make friends
Sizinle ilgilenmek istiyorlar ama onlarla arkadaşlık kurmaya çalışın
and try to know them, hardly you know their names, hardly,
ve onları tanımaya çalışın, onların isimlerini zar zor biliyorsunuz,
you write to them. That's not proper.
onlara yazın. Bu uygun değil.
So at least those who have been here many a times,
Yani en azından pek çok kez gelmiş olanlar
should try to know the names of the people,
insanların isimlerini bilmeye çalışmalılar,
take their addresses and they may also write to you
onların adreslerini alın ve onlar da size yazabilirler
and you may also write to them.
ve sizler de onlara yazabilirsiniz.
So that you maintain a proper correspondence.
Uygun bir haberleşmeyi sürdürün.
So this relationship, of friendship and love
Yani bu ilişki, arkadaşlık ve sevgi ilişkisi başlamalıdır,
must be started as Shri Krishna has said
Shri Krishna’nın dediği gibi,
that unless and until you love each other
“siz birbirinizi sevmedikçe,
I do not exist with in you.
Ben sizlerin içinde olmayacağım.”
So it is not only one country, it is not many countries,
Bu sadece tek bir ülke değil, bu pek çok ülke değil,
it's all the countries of the world have to love each other
dünyadaki bütün ülkeler birbirlerini sevmeliler
and to understand each other as yogis.
ve Yogiler olarak birbirlerini anlamalılar.
You are all yogis and to be appreciated.
Hepiniz Yogilersiniz ve bu takdir edilecek.
They are already singing the praises of you since long
Onlar uzun zamandır size övgü şarkıları söylüyorlar
and now it is time to prove it.
ve şimdi bunu kanıtlamanın zamanı.
The other day I described to them the procession
Geçen gün onlara tören alayımızın İngiliz bir şair  tarafından
that was described by one of the English poets
tarif edilmiş olduğunu onlara izah ettim.  Şair vizyonunda
in his vision he saw our procession and when I told them
bizim tören alayımızı gördü ve onlara bunu söylediğim zaman,
they are very happy that already an English poet like Lewis could
Lewis gibi bir İngiliz şairin bu noktayı görebilmiş olmasına ve
see these points and written in such details the whole description.
herşeyi  böyle detaylı  yazmış olmasından dolayı çok mutluydular
But that book has not arrived in India, Vision.  It is a beautiful book
ama bu kitap Hindistan’a ulaşmadı henüz-Vizyon. Bu güzel bir kitap
and I would request the Australians to, if possible
ve Avusturalyalılardan rica etmeliyim, kopyalarını yapmak üzere
to make some copies of that and handed it over,
kitabı onlara teslim etmek mümkünse, en azından
at least the typed copies,
daktilo edilmiş kopyalarını,
in Southara or in Sangli somehow if you have the book with you
Southara’da veya Sangli’de bir şekilde, eğer yanınızda kitap varsa,
and give it to them. They will be very happy, know all about it.
onlara verin. Bütün bunları bilmekten dolayı çok mutlu olacaklardır.
That will be a special present to the people of Ganapatipule.
Bu Ganapatipule’liler için özel bir hediye olacaktır.
If you could give the exact,  book
Eğer tam kitabı onlara verebilirseniz o zaman birileri
then somebody can do it in Southara and can do it in one day  in India
Southara’da yapabilir. Onlar bunu, bir günde yapabilirler,
these things can be done very easily in India.
Hindistan’da bu şeyler çok kolayca yapılabilir.
We don't book things as you have to book.
Bizim, sizin gibi  kaydettirmemiz gerekmiyor.
We have started but not so much of booking this year.
Başladık ama burada çok fazla kayıt yok.
So I request you do that much,
Bu yüzden sizden bu kadarını rica ediyorum,
give the book to these people, so they will bring it printed
bu insanlara kitabı verin, onlar basılmış halde geri getireceklerdir
and everybody can have it.
ve herkes kitaba sahip olabilir.